# **Dayo Lawal**

Born 19th of January 1995 xtremestringx2011@gmail. com +2349026188784

CERTIFICATES

# ASSOCIATIONS

# Zion tribe International

President/ Founder

# Student Chemical Association Lokoja

President/ Director of Socials

#### LANGUAGES

#### Yoruba

Spoken: Fluent • Written: Fluent

#### **English**

Spoken: Fluent • Written: Fluent

### INTRO

A highly dedicated and diligent personality with 2 years experience in Manufacturing processing of FMCG such as the quality, technical and production aspects.

I have the ability to work under immense pressure with the sole purpose of achieving success.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Chemical Process Engineer(NYSC) Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Jun 2022 - Sep 2022

I was involved in the preparation of the chemicals such as the acids and solutions used in the treatment of the cans, operation of the machine, maintenance of the whole process, observing consistent housekeeping, also the hourly quality checks done on the cans to ensure they meet the required specifications

# Palletizer Operator(NYSC)

Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • May 2022 - Sep 2022

Close monitoring of the cans coming from the infeed belt to ensure they follow the proper pattern into the palletizer, fixing of the strapper and wrapper, correction of faults encountered while on operation, operation of the machine, working directly with the Quality Assurance personnels, also running quality checks on cans such as dome reverse.

# LSM can maker(NYSC)

Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Apr 2022 - Sep 2022

Monitoring and cleaning of the lacquer spraying machine, operation of the machine, maintaining the pressure values between the actual and calibrated pressure, quality checks such as HME test, adhesion test etc

# Front End Operator (NYSC)

Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Mar 2022 - Sep 2022

I was in charge of the quality checks of the cups and cans, changing of aluminum coils, corrections of faults, removing of jammed cans, operation of machine and maintenance of the bodymakers.

#### Decorator Can maker(NYSC) Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Jan 2022 - Sep 2022

Filling of inks and close monitoring of the sprayed cans, fixing of new plates, changing of labels, carrying operation on the machine, quality checks on the cans such as the viscosity, film weight, carrying out monthly maintenance on the decorators.

# Finished Pallet Inspector (NYSC) Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

Worked closely with the palletizer operatives, visual and quality checks on the palletized cans as the final process before going into the warehouse, placing of pallet tickets.

# Line Auditor(NYSC)

Nampak Bevcan Nigeria • Nov 2021 - Sep 2022

Worked closely with the finished pallet Inspector, detailed all operation done during the shift, ensuring that all the quality checks done meets their specifications.

# **Quality Assurance Intern**

Nasco Household Products Limited • Jun 2018 - Nov 2018

Supervision of the detergent production, ensuring the detergent produced meets the company's standard, quality checks on the detergent, stock counting.

# Wet laboratory analyst (INTERN)

National Metallurgical Development Centre • Apr 2018 - Jun 2018

I assisted the Head of Laboratory in the day to day activities in the Laboratory, observing house keeping, production of chemicals used in the separation of metals from their ores, chemical experiments on the metals knowing their characteristics and specifications, operation of the UV spectroscopy.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of science**

Federal University Lokoja • Oct 2015 - Nov 2021

I read pure and applied chemistry and focused more on the analytical and industrial part, my final year project was based on the Adsorption Characteristics of sediments in River Niger.

Secondary School Certificate Examination St John's college Jos Plateau state • Sep 2005 - Jul 2011

First School leaving Certificate

Gaskiya Highland Private School Jos Plateau state • Sep 1999 - Jul 2005

Basic Primary school



#### SKILLS

Internal communicationEntrepreneurshipBudgeting, financial planningBusiness managementOffice tools: Word, Excel, OutlookSocial media usage (Facebook, Twitter, etc.)PhotoshopGraphical design toolsBasic computer maintenanceEngineeringTroubleshootingQuality control and supervisionProduct managementQuality managementPerformance monitoring and evaluation



# HOBBIES

Singing

Content writing

Video games

Playing guitar



### LINKS

Dayo Lawal